A Guide to the Dana Harmon Papers, 1885-1916
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Dana Harmon Papers, 1885-1916
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2011-013
1.0 cu. ft. 2 boxes
The collection consists of papers collected by and about Dana Harmon. They include corespondence, newspaper clippings, receipts, scrapbook, summons for the Grand Jury, and lists of supporters and people asked for support.
Harmon, Dana
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Dana Harmon Papers were acquired by the Special Collection prior to 2011.
Biographical Note
Dana Harmon ran as a Republican nominee for Judge of the First Judicial Circuit of Tennessee. He ran with Hon. S. B. Kefauver, Republican Nominee for Attorney General of the First Judicial Circuit of Tennessee. In 1916, he ran in the primary for congress as a Republican candidate.
Harmon presided over J.R. Wilson v. C. P. Faw in 1916. He was seen as appealing in error from the Circuit Court of Washington County, making this a leading case of the Court of Civil Appeals in Tennessee.
Scope and Content
The collection contains papers by and about Dana Harmon. The two boxes contain a number of files, containing correspondence, newspaper clippings, receipts, scrapbook, summons for the Grand Jury, and lists of supporters and people asked for support.
A majority of the papers consists of letters written to or from Harmon, often with a response on the verso side. Other types of materials include court expense documents, family and genealogy papers relating to the Harmons, and information on the history of Greenville, TN. There is also a group of personal papers: receipts, telegraphs, masonic membership items, and a scrapbook of Harmon's run for 1st District County in Tennessee, documented through newspaper clippings.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by material type. Correspondence, located in Box 1, is in chronological order.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1901. (Box-folder 1-1)
- Correspondence, January-March 1902. (Box-folder 1-2)
- Correspondence, April-June 1902. (Box-folder 1-3)
- Correspondence, July-September 1902. (Box-folder 1-4)
- Correspondence, October-December 1902. (Box-folder 1-5)
- Correspondence, n.d. (Box-folder 1-6)
- Expenses, 1885-1892. (Box-folder 2-1)
- Expenses, 1888. (Box-folder 2-2)
- Family History Papers. (Box-folder 2-3)
- Harmon Asking for Support and Reply. (Box-folder 2-4)
- Name Lists. (Box-folder 2-5)
- Receipts and Other Papers. (Box-folder 2-6)
- Republican Judicial Executive Committee Headquarters Correspondence. (Box-folder 2-7)
- Scrapbook. (Box-folder 2-8)